A Guide to the Norfolk Public School Papers, 1922-2006
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
- The Path to a Unitary School District 1960-1983
  - Exhibits A-D 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:16)
  - NAACP Response to the 1971-1972 Plan 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18:17)
  - 4th Circuit Court of Appeals Transcript 1972 March 7 (Box-folder 18:18)
  - 4th Circuit Court of Appeals Transcript 1972 March 8 (Box-folder 18:19)
  - H.R. 13915 20 March 1972 (Box-folder 18:20)
  - Court Order Approving Changes 16 June 1972 (Box-folder 18:21)
  - Richmond Case 1972 (Box-folder 18:22)
  - Counsel Fees 1972 June 28 (Box-folder 19:1)
  - Fall 1972 Report to the Court 1972 (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Desegregation Study 1972 August 14-18 (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Transition Study 1972 August 3 (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Transition School 1972 August 3 (Box-folder 19:4)
  - Full Time Professional Instructional Staff 1972 October 2 (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Race Distribution of Faculty 1972 November 10 (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Final Argument 1972 October 26 (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Depositions 1972 (Box-folder 19:8)
  - Richmond Transcripts 1972 (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Integration Plaintiff Counsel Fees 1972-1972 (Box-folder 19:10)
  - Transportation 1972-1973 (Box-folder 19:11)
  - Exceptions of Plaintifffs 1972 July 21 (Box-folder 19:12)
  - District Court 1972 July 11 (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Proposed Adjustments to Pupil Attendance Plan 1972 (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Integration-1972-1973, Federal Court Memorandums, Motions, Orders 1972-1972 (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Proposed Adjustments to Plan 1972 May 25 (Box-folder 20:4)
  - Capacity Data 1973 (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Attorneys Fees 1973 January 22 (Box-folder 20:6)
  - Proposed Adjustment to Pupil Attendance Plan 1973 (Box-folder 20:7)
  - Administrative Staff by Race 1973 (Box-folder 20:8)
  - Desegregation-Miscellaneous 1973-1981 (Box-folder 20:9)
  - Review of Federal Court Orders 1973 November 16 (Box-folder 20:10)
  - Fall 1973 Report to the Court 1973 (Box-folder 20:11)
  - Integration 1973-1974, Pupil Attendance Plan 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20:12)
  - Minority and Non-Minority Percentages Summary 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20:13)
  - Pupil Reassignment Factors 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20:14)
  - Integration History 1974 (Box-folder 20:15)
  - Amendments to the Assignment Plan 1974-1975 (Box-folder 20:16)
  - Fall 1974 Report to the Court 1974 (Box-folder 20:17)
  - Integration 1974-1975 Pupil Assignment Plan (Box-folder 20:18)
  - Order-Beckett Dismissal 1974 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - Opinions from Other Districts 1974 (Box-folder 21:2)
  - Order Labeling Norfolk as a Unitary School District 1975 February (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Attorney General Opinions 1976 (Box-folder 21:4)
  - Desegregation-Miscellaneous Reports, Guidelines 1976 (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Supreme Court-Hortonville 1976 (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Racial Distribution Administrators 1977 (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Attendance Percentage, 1978-1979 to 1982-1983 1983 (Box-folder 21:8)
  - NAACP 1979 (Box-folder 21:9)
  - Coleman Report 21:10 (Box-folder 21:10)
- Norfolk as a Unitary School District and the End of Busing 1976-1991
  - News Clippings 1980 (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Desegregation, Nashville, TN 1980-1981 (Box-folder 22:2-4)
  - Brown, Carlton E. Study 1980-1981 (Box-folder 22:5)
  - Desegregation, Shreveport, LA Plan and Visit 1981 (Box-folder 22:6)
  - Desegregation Plan, Norfolk 1981 August 14 (Box-folder 22:7)
  - Desegregation of NPS Impact Report, Michigan State 1982 March 29 (Box-folder 22:8)
  - Dr. David Armor 1982-1988 (Box-folder 23:1-5)
  - Pupil Assignments and Reassignments 1976-1983 (Box-folder 23:6-7)
  - School Closures 1981 (Box-folder 24:1)
  - Norfolk Tea Party 1981 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Norfolk Branch NAACP Education Position Paper 1982 February 4 (Box-folder 24:3)
  - Norfolk Coalition for Quality Public Education 1982 (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Majority Minority Transfer Option 1982-1983 (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Transportation Info 1983 (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Preparation for Court 1983 (Box-folder 1983)
  - Elementary Organization 1983 September (Box-folder 24:8-9)
  - Proposal for Voluntary Stably Desegregated System 1983 January (Box-folder 24:10)
  - Senior High Master Schedules 1983 (Box-folder 24:11)
  - Junior High Master Schedules 1983 (Box-folder 24:12)
  - Depositions Riddick v. School Board 1983 November (Box-folder 24:13-14)
  - Review of Busing, Norfolk, VA -- Wilson 1983 (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Board Letter Voluntary Desegregation of School System to End Busing 1983 (Box-folder 25:2)
  - Review of Busing, Norfolk, VA--Wilson 1983 (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Neighborhood Schools 1982-1983 and 1983-1984 (Box-folder 25:3)
  - Resolution of the School Board-Neighborhood School Plan 1983 (Box-folder 25:4)
  - Riddick Case 1984 (Box-folder 25:5)
  - Neighborhood Plan 1984 (Box-folder 25:6)
  - Plaintiffs First Supp. Response to Defendants First 1984 (Box-folder 25:7)
  - New Pupil Assignment Plan 1984-1985 (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Desegregation, 1984 Trial 1984 (Box-folder 25:9)
  - Collins et al v. City of Norfolk et al. 1984 (Box-folder 25:10)
  - Court Documents 1984-1986 (Box-folder 25:11)
  - Transportation Consultant (Ketron) 1985 (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Desegregation 1986 (Box-folder 26:1)
  - DecisionUS Court of Appeals for 4th Circuit & Appeal by Attorneys for Petitioners 1986 February 12 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - Allocation of Resources Report (Neighborhood School Plan) 1987 August 20 (Box-folder 26:3)
  - Community Oversight Committee 1986-1987 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - Community Oversight Committee Reports 1987-1988 (Box-folder 26:5)
  - Court Order 1989 (Box-folder 26:6)
  - Community Oversight Committee 1987-1990 (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Community Oversight Committee 1989 (Box-folder 27:2)
  - Community Oversight Committee Reports 1987-1991 (Box-folder 27:3)
  - Greer, Jack Attorney at Law 1976-1980 (Box-folder 27:4-6)
  - Greer, Jack Attorney at Law 1976-1980 (Box-folder 28:1-3)
  - Neighborhood School Planning 1983-1986 (Box-folder 28:4-5)
  - Total Full-Time Instructional Staff n.d. (Box-folder 28:6)
  - Jr. High Feeder Plan n.d. (Box-folder 28:7)
  - Junior HS with 9th Graders at Sr. High n.d. (Box-folder 28:8)
  - Legal Status of Neighborhood School n.d. (Box-folder 28:9)
  - Requests for Late Buses n.d. (Box-folder 28:10)
  - Norfolk Public Schools & Auxiliary Educational Facilities n.d. (Box-folder 28:11)
- Directories and Calendars 1922-2006
  - Calendars 1952-1953 to 1956-1957 (Box-folder 29:1)
  - Calendars 1957-1958 to 1959-1960 (Box-folder 29:2)
  - Calendars 1960-1961 to 1965-1966 (Box-folder 29:3)
  - Calendars 1966-1967 to 1967-1968 (Box-folder 29:4)
  - Calendars 1968-1969 to 1969-1970 (Box-folder 29:5)
  - Calendars 1970-1971 to 1972-1973 (Box-folder 30:1)
  - Calendars 1973-1974 to 1975-1976 (Box-folder 30:2)
  - Calendars 1976-1977 to 1978-1979 (Box-folder 30:3)
  - Calendars 1979-1980 to 1981-1982 (Box-folder 30:4)
  - Calendars 1982-1983 to 1984-1985 (Box-folder 31:1)
  - Calendars 1985-1986 to 1986-1987 (Box-folder 31:2)
  - Calendars 1987-1988 to 1988-1989 (Box-folder 31:3)
  - Calendars 1989-1990 to 1990-1991 (Box-folder 31:4)
  - Calendars 1991-1992 to 1992-1993 (Box-folder 31:5)
  - Calendars 1993-1994 to 1994-1995 (Box-folder 32:1)
  - Calendars 1995-1996 to 1996-1997 (Box-folder 32:2)
  - Calendars 2000-2001 (Box-folder 32:3)
  - Calendars 2005-2006 (Box-folder 32:4)
  - Directories 1922-1923 to 1948-1949 (Box-folder 32:5)
  - Directories 1950-1951 to 1960-1961 (Box-folder 33:1)
  - Directories 1964-1965 to 1965-1966 (Box-folder 33:2)
  - Directories 1966-1967 to 1967-1968 (Box-folder 33:3)
  - Directories 1969-1970 to 1970-1971 (Box-folder 33:4)
  - Directories 1971-1972 to 1972-1973 (Box-folder 33:5)
  - Directories 1973-1974 to 1974-1975 (Box-folder 33:6)
  - Directories 1975-1976 to 1976-1977 (Box-folder 33:7)
  - Directories 1977-1978 to 1978-1979 (Box-folder 33:8)
  - Directories 1979-1980 to 1980-1981 (Box-folder 34:1)
  - Directories 1981-1982 to 1982-1983 (Box-folder 34:2)
  - Directories 1983-1990 (Box-folder 34:3)
- Oversized Documents
  - Attendance Zones 1980s (Box-folder 35:1)
  - Exhibits 1-5 1970 (Box-folder 35:2)
  - Addendum to Resolutions 1965 (Box-folder 35:3)
  - Recommended Assignment of Pupils 1960-1961 (Box-folder 35:4)
  - Dr. David Armor Study (test score printouts) 1983 (Box-folder 36:1)
  - Stat Race Count/Breakdown by School 1984 (Box-folder 36:2)
  - Print Outs Neighborhood Schools 1984 (Box-folder 36:3)
  - Jack Greer 1984 (Box-folder 36:4)